<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-27T21:04:38+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/</id><title type="html">My Unplastic Life</title><subtitle>Trying to de-plasticify my life!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Packaging Alternatives</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/problem-plastic-packaging/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Packaging Alternatives" /><published>2018-01-27T19:46:58+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-27T19:46:58+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/problem-plastic-packaging</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/problem-plastic-packaging/">&lt;p&gt;Week 4 - Packaging Alternatives&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continue to venture further along my plastic-free journey, although I am finding more and more things covered in plastic packaging, I am also discovering alternatives. This week I had the hard job of trying out a new chocolate brand - Eat Your Hat. Not only is it fair-trade and organic, I was delighted to discover when opening the packet that the wrapper inside is plant based. This means you can actually put it in the compost! And not only this - the chocolate is delicious! I tried the cardamom version, but I am looking forward to trying out all the different flavours. If you are a chocolate lover it is hard to find brands which aren’t wrapped in plastic. But don’t worry I am up for the challenge of discovering which brands aren’t!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eatyourhat.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eatyourhat.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.eatyourhat.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/27/IMG_20180125_181045_025.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eat your hat bar&quot; title=&quot;Eat your hat bar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also been delighted to hear that glass-milk bottles are on the rise. I have been buying my milk in returnable glass bottles from Suffolk Farmhouse Cheeses. They run a diary just up the road from me, where you can also buy milk from their vending machine. The cows are also raised in a higher-welfare system. Suffolk Farmhouse Cheeses have just installed a state-of-the-art milking system which gives their cows the freedom to choose when they are milked. So it’s better for the environment and better for the cows - win, win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.suffolkcheese.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;http://www.suffolkcheese.co.uk/&quot;&gt;http://www.suffolkcheese.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/27/IMG_20180124_092652_861.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 4 - Packaging Alternatives</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22%22,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Plasticy Stroll in the Countryside</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Plasticy Stroll in the Countryside" /><published>2018-01-21T19:39:55+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:39:55+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-3/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-3---a-plasticy-stroll-in-the-countryside&quot;&gt;Week 3 - A Plasticy Stroll in the Countryside&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a lovely sunny day on Sunday so we decided to take the children for a walk. Not long after we had set off I noticed a small piece of plastic in the hedge. The hedges have recently been trimmed and as we walked further we began to notice more and more. I think this plastic is always there but unless you are looking for it you don’t particularly notice it. We decided to collect all the plastic we came across (luckily I had some bio-degradable dog bags in my pocket to collect it in!). By the end of our two mile walk you can see we had picked up quite a lot - some of it crisp and chocolate bar packaging but also lots of bigger pieces which were half buried in the ground.  My new pledge is to pick up at least three pieces of plastic everytime I am out walking in the countryside. A report in Science Magazine estimates that 8.3bn tonnes of plastic has been produced to date. Of this, 6.3bn tonnes of plastic is now waste – a majority of which, some 79%, is in landfill or the natural environment. Of this 6.3bn tonnes only 9% is recycled. If everyone made this pledge think what a difference this could make!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as collecting rubbish I have also been on a quest to find plastic-free cereal. When I can’t buy from local shops I prefer to support the local Co-op rather than some of the bigger supermarket chains due to their ethical credentials. So rather than buying Weetabix (which I knew was wrapped in paper), I bought the Co-op’s own brand instead. I was horrified when my children opened the box to find that the biscuits were wrapped in plastic. I quickly sent the following email to Customer Services, and am yet to hear a reply! Weetabix reverted back to paper after using film in 2012, not because it was better environmentally, but because it is easier to open. I will stick to Weetabix in the future and begin making my own muesli and granola in the future, watch this space for recipes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/weetabix.jpg&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Sir/Madam,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing to enquire why you wrap your wholewheat biscuits in plastic rather than paper like Weetabix do? I believe you to be an ethical company, one of the reasons why I choose to support you rather than other supermarkets, I am surprised that you do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ethical policy on sustainable development states that nature cannot stand a progressive build up of societies waste, particularly materials that cannot degrade into harmless substances and that you recognise that this is a minimum requirement for ecological sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using non-recyclable, single use plastic seems to go completely against this, particularly when there are other viable alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing your reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E.Sheldrake&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 3 - A Plasticy Stroll in the Countryside</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Trouble with Toothpaste</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Trouble with Toothpaste" /><published>2018-01-12T19:39:55+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-12T19:39:55+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-2/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-2---the-trouble-with-toothpaste&quot;&gt;Week 2 - The Trouble with Toothpaste&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have been mainly troubled by toothpaste! So my toothpaste tube has finally got to the point of needing replacing. I didn’t really know where to start looking for a plastic-free toothpaste alternative. I wasn’t overly optimistic after a quick google search came up with nothing. In fact one website stated that no-one manufactured metal toothpaste tubes anymore. I wasn’t keen to start making my own so I went to my local town. I walked past Holland and Barrett and thought that would be a good place to try as they sell a lot of alternative products. They did indeed sell a range of eco and organic toothpaste but all in plastic tubes. After trying a few other places I decided to look in a large local supermarket (naming no names!) and was very surprised to find Euthymol Toothpaste in a metal tube. Although it has a plastic lid I thought this was the best next option before I pluck up the courage to make my own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2836/8947738178_195b5aa707_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Euthymol&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 2 - The Trouble with Toothpaste</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Post-Christmas Blues</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post-Christmas Blues" /><published>2018-01-07T19:39:55+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-07T19:39:55+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-1/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-1---post-christmas-blues&quot;&gt;Week 1 - Post-Christmas Blues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first week of myunplasticlife hasn’t been too much of a challenge! Mainly because having just having had Christmas I haven’t felt the need to go shopping. I’m sure hurdles will soon be standing in my way when I begin to run out of supplies. I’m also very lucky to have easy access to the family business - Alder Carr Farm Shop which is also pledging to go plastic free. This means I can easily get many of my staples, in particular fruit and vegetables which in the supermarkets are surrounding in packaging, completely plastic free!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 1 - Post-Christmas Blues</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry></feed>