<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-25T21:04:32+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/</id><title type="html">My Unplastic Life</title><subtitle>Trying to de-plasticify my life!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Toxic Ticking Timebomb?</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/a-toxic-ticking-timebomb/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Toxic Ticking Timebomb?" /><published>2018-02-25T19:39:20+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-25T19:39:20+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/a-toxic-ticking-timebomb</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/a-toxic-ticking-timebomb/">&lt;p&gt;Week 8 - A Toxic Ticking Timebomb?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/25/downloadfile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Plastic bottles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BPA, otherwise known as Bisphenol-A, is a chemical which is added to many plastic to make them strong and resilient. It has been added to plastics since the 1950s and is found in all sorts of products from baby bottles to food containers. It is also used to make epoxy resins to put on the inside of cans to stop them corroding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/25/2423199243_647afcfa1e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Baby Bottles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent study by Exeter University found that 86% of teenagers now have BPA in their bodies. This is because BPA can be absorbed through skin contact. The chemical leaches out of the plastic and can then be ingested or absorbed through the skin. Due to the wide range of products that contain BPA it is difficult to avoid it altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how dangerous is BPA? This is still highly debated but BPA is said to mimic the structure of the hormone oestrogen, and therefore interfere with the production of natural hormones. This can lead to all sorts of health problems. Young children and foetuses are particularly at risk as they have underdeveloped systems for detoxifying chemicals.  Research suggests that BPA is linked to cardiovascular problems, type-2 diabetes, breast and prostrate cancer and fetal brain development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the exact risks are still unknown many companies are becoming BPA free and even the European Food Safety Authority to reduce the acceptable daily intake of BPA. So how can I reduce my exposure to BPA? It will be practically impossible to avoid it completely as it is in so many products but there are a number of things you can do to avoid it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drink only tap water or use a refillable metal bottle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid canned foods and buy products in cardboard or glass containers, unless they state they are BPA-free&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pack your own lunches using metal containers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eat freshly prepared foods which haven’t been wrapped in plastic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use wooden utensils for cooking with&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use metal or glass containers for storing left-overs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a metal percolator or cafetière to make your daily coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/25/glassjars.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Glass Jars&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Toxic plastic" /><summary type="html">Week 8 - A Toxic Ticking Timebomb?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22%22,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Plastic-free Family</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/plastic-free-family/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plastic-free Family" /><published>2018-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/plastic-free-family</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/plastic-free-family/">&lt;p&gt;Week 7 - Plastic-free Family&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been amazing to see how my plastic-free pledge is not only having a positive effect on me, but also my whole family too. My 10 year-old has been inspired by my efforts to write this amazing poem!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/17/Isaac-poem.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also now can’t go out for a walk without stopping to pick up rubbish. We took a walk along the River Deben in half term and didn’t find a single piece of plastic. What a contrast to our walk around Needham Lake! It was very sad to see so much plastic, particularly evident due to the recent hedge trimming, which revealed a lot of previously hidden rubbish. My son also took it upon himself to document the occasion with these pictures (apart from the one of him!). I think you’ll agree that one of the plastic bags we found had a rather ironic message on it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/17/Plastic walk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the dogs have been helping us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/17/Plasticwalk2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironic plastic bag message - well done Tesco!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/17/Plasticwalk3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our total haul&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/17/Photographer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budding photographer&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="family" /><summary type="html">Week 7 - Plastic-free Family</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22%22,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Massage Candle Recipe</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/articles/massage-candle-recipe/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Massage Candle Recipe" /><published>2018-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/articles/massage-candle-recipe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/articles/massage-candle-recipe/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massage Candle Recipe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a simple concept, and so easy to make! Completely plastic-free and you’ll save money too - I have seen these for sale on the internet for £17! The candles are made from pure ingredients which when burnt will melt to body temperature. They can then be rubbed on the skin. A gorgeous candle which is also a lush moisturiser!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Candle ingredients.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you need:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 oz of beeswax&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 oz cocoa or shea butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1oz sweet almond or jojoba oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10-20 drops of essential oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A jar or tin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-waxed wick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Double boiler - I used a saucepan and a ceramic bowl&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knife&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wooden chopstick x 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got all my ingredients from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesoapkitchen.co.uk&quot; title=&quot;The Soap Kitchen&quot;&gt;The Soap Kitchen&lt;/a&gt; but there are lots of places to get all your supplies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.Place your wick into your tin or jar, I tied the top to a chopstick to keep it up straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Wick in jar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;2. Cut your wax and butter into small pieces so they melt quickly and evenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. Put your saucepan on the hob with a small amount of water in the bottom. Bring to a simmer and then place your ceramic bowl on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.Over a medium heat gently stir the wax, butter and almond oil until melted - this will take 2-5 minutes. Don’t over heat the mixture or create too many bubbles when you’re mixing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Bowl on hob.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;5. Take the bowl off the heat and pour in your essential oils and give another stir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the mixture into your jar and leave to cool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Pour mixture in jar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;7. Once solid it is ready to use - just cut the wick from the chop stick and you are ready to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8. Light the wick and when you have some melted oil, pour it into your hand. You can now use it as a regular massage oil with the added benefit that it is already warm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/litcandlejar1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Eleanor_Sheldrake</name></author><summary type="html">A gorgeous candle which is also a lush moisturiser!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/uploads/2018/02/12/Finishedcandle.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Plastic-free Valentine</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/my-plastic-free-valentine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Plastic-free Valentine" /><published>2018-02-11T14:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-11T14:12:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/my-plastic-free-valentine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/my-plastic-free-valentine/">&lt;p&gt;Week 6 - My Plastic-free Valentine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Valentinesday-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Hearts hanging in a tree&quot; title=&quot;Hearts in Tree&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valentine’s Day can be a bit of a minefield for plastic packaging. Traditional gifts, like bunches of flowers and boxes of chocolates, tend to be covered in plastic making it difficult to find an alternative. So here is your guide to a totally plastic-free day your loved one will remember!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treat your loved one to a romantic, candle-lit massage using a home-made massage candle. Sounds complicated? It’s really easy - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/articles/&quot;&gt;see my articles&lt;/a&gt; for how to make your own!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get crafty - most cards seem to come wrapped in plastic, so to avoid this make your own! There are loads of ideas on pinterest if you need some inspiration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go on a romantic walk - the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationaltrust.org.uk/lists/top-spots-for-a-sprinkle-of-romance&quot; title=&quot;National Trust Romantic walks&quot;&gt;National Trust&lt;/a&gt; has a great list of the top romantic walks in the UK&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write some romantic IOU vouchers - or &lt;a href=&quot;https://glitternspice.com/romantic-and-naughty-printable-love-coupons/&quot; title=&quot;Glitter and Spice &quot;&gt;Glitter and Spice&lt;/a&gt; have printable ones to save you time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make your own chocolates to avoid the plastic - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thekitchn.com/how-to-make-simple-foolproof-chocolate-truffles-252063&quot; title=&quot;The Kitchn&quot;&gt;The Kitchn&lt;/a&gt; have a really easy recipe, with step-by-step instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook your Valentine their favourite meal. Seems like a simple idea but who doesn’t love being cooked for - as long as you wash up too?!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dedicate them a song on the radio - get a mention on their favourite radio station, just make sure you send them a link to the broadcast so they don’t miss it!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give them the gift of an experience, there are loads of websites dedicated to finding the perfect experience they will love.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make them a hamper containing all their favourite goodies - choose a basket or hamper from your local craft shop and then fill it with all their favourite things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plastic-free flowers - most bouquets come wrapped in plastic, to avoid this buy loose flowers from your local florist and then wrap them yourself at home using brown paper and plastic-free twine. Your Valentine is sure to appreciate the extra effort you have gone to!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Valentine’s Day!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 6 - My Plastic-free Valentine</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Natural, Plastic-free Toothpaste</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/natural-plastic-free-toothpaste/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Natural, Plastic-free Toothpaste" /><published>2018-02-04T17:04:49+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-04T17:04:49+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/natural-plastic-free-toothpaste</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/natural-plastic-free-toothpaste/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week 5 - Natural, Plastic-free Toothpaste&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have decided to bite the bullet and try out my own toothpaste recipes (and my new Humble toothbrush!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some initial concerns about not using fluoride so decided to do some research. According to livescience.com the addition of fluoride in toothpaste is to chemically strengthen the teeth, making them more resistant to the breakdown by acids, which leads to cavities. But not everyone needs added fluoride - some people are naturally resistant due to a high fluoride content in their teeth (but if you are or not is hard to tell!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fluoride has been added to our drinking water and toothpaste for the last 65 years in which time tooth decay rapidly declined. In the past, 95% of people suffered from cavities! The addition of fluoride is a contentious issue.  Could the addition of fluoride and the decline in tooth decay be a coincidence? I came across many websites that say tooth health has improved as our diet has improved, in fact Public Health England does say that tooth health is worse in areas of deprivation, maybe due to a poor diet. There are also some websites stating links between fluoride and osteoporosis, thyroid problems, endocrine problems and cancers but they do not state the source of their information.  The NHS website highlights some of the health concerns including dental fluorosis, but the in depth reports state no link between water fluoridation and many non-dental indicators such as Down’s syndrome, cancer and cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you live on a natural diet, not containing too many sugars your teeth will be healthier. But if you are still concerned about not getting enough fluoride, when using a natural toothpaste, there are a number of ways to get the fluoride you need to protect your teeth. You could use fluoride mouthwash, fluoride gel, take a fluoride supplement or even use wooden fluoride dental sticks! Other ways to help protect your teeth - floss daily and avoid sugar!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural, Plastic-free, Toothpaste recipe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/04/20180204_161334.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Ingredients&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix together 2 tbsp of coconut oil, 2 tbsp baking powder, 1 tsp turmeric (optional), ½ tsp salt and 2 ground cloves. Add a few drops of water to help mix the ingredients and improve the texture. If it is too coarse, you might to run it through a food processor first.  How does it taste? I think savoury toothpaste may take some getting used to! I think next time I will try a more traditional, minty version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/04/20180204_165843-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best ingredients for natural toothpaste:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coconut oil - can help boost the microbiome in your gut and there is also some evidence that coconut oil can help reduce bacteria which cause cavities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crushed cacao nibs - compounds in cacao beans promote remineralisation just like fluoride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bentonite clay - is a natural polisher, rich in minerals. It’s also alkaline, so it helps reduce acidity in the mouth. It is slightly abrasive so only use once or twice a week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xylitol reduces cavity-causing bacteria in the mouth. Don’t add too much as it is a sweetener.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Baking soda - it is alkaline and can help neutralise acids in your mouth. It is also not too abrasive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt - naturally alkaline to reduce acidity in the mouth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turmeric - surprisingly, despite it staining everything it comes into contact with, turmeric is a natural tooth whitener!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spices or essential oils for flavour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 5 - Natural, Plastic-free Toothpaste</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3Enil,%20%22creditlink%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Natural, plastic-free toothpaste recipe</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/articles/natural-plastic-free-toothpaste-recipe/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Natural, plastic-free toothpaste recipe" /><published>2018-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/articles/natural-plastic-free-toothpaste-recipe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/articles/natural-plastic-free-toothpaste-recipe/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural, Plastic-free, Toothpaste recipe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/04/20180204_161334.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix together 2 tbsp of coconut oil, 2 tbsp baking powder, 1 tsp turmeric (optional), ½ tsp salt and 2 ground cloves. Add a few drops of water to help mix the ingredients and improve the texture. If it is too coarse, you might to run it through a food processor first.  How does it taste? I think savoury toothpaste may take some getting used to! I think next time I will try a more traditional, minty version!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/04/20180204_165843-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best ingredients for natural toothpaste:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coconut oil - can help boost the microbiome in your gut and there is also some evidence that coconut oil can help reduce bacteria which cause cavities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crushed cacao nibs - compounds in cacao beans promote remineralisation just like fluoride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bentonite clay - is a natural polisher, rich in minerals. It’s also alkaline, so it helps reduce acidity in the mouth. It is slightly abrasive so only use once or twice a week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xylitol reduces cavity-causing bacteria in the mouth. Don’t add too much as it is a sweetener.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Baking soda - it is alkaline and can help neutralise acids in your mouth. It is also not too abrasive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seasalt - naturally alkaline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turmeric - surprisingly, despite it staining everything it comes into contact with, turmeric is a natural tooth whitener!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spices or essential oils for flavour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Eleanor_Sheldrake</name></author><category term="toothpaste" /><summary type="html">A guide to making your own toothpaste.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/uploads/2018/02/04/20180204_161334.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Packaging Alternatives</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/problem-plastic-packaging/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Packaging Alternatives" /><published>2018-01-27T19:46:58+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-27T19:46:58+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/problem-plastic-packaging</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/problem-plastic-packaging/">&lt;p&gt;Week 4 - Packaging Alternatives&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continue to venture further along my plastic-free journey, although I am finding more and more things covered in plastic packaging, I am also discovering alternatives. This week I had the hard job of trying out a new chocolate brand - Eat Your Hat. Not only is it fair-trade and organic, I was delighted to discover when opening the packet that the wrapper inside is plant based. This means you can actually put it in the compost! And not only this - the chocolate is delicious! I tried the cardamom version, but I am looking forward to trying out all the different flavours. If you are a chocolate lover it is hard to find brands which aren’t wrapped in plastic. But don’t worry I am up for the challenge of discovering which brands aren’t!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eatyourhat.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eatyourhat.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.eatyourhat.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/27/IMG_20180125_181045_025.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eat your hat bar&quot; title=&quot;Eat your hat bar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also been delighted to hear that glass-milk bottles are on the rise. I have been buying my milk in returnable glass bottles from Suffolk Farmhouse Cheeses. They run a diary just up the road from me, where you can also buy milk from their vending machine. The cows are also raised in a higher-welfare system. Suffolk Farmhouse Cheeses have just installed a state-of-the-art milking system which gives their cows the freedom to choose when they are milked. So it’s better for the environment and better for the cows - win, win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.suffolkcheese.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;http://www.suffolkcheese.co.uk/&quot;&gt;http://www.suffolkcheese.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/27/IMG_20180124_092652_861.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 4 - Packaging Alternatives</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3Enil,%20%22creditlink%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Plasticy Stroll in the Countryside</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Plasticy Stroll in the Countryside" /><published>2018-01-21T19:39:55+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-21T19:39:55+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-3/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-3---a-plasticy-stroll-in-the-countryside&quot;&gt;Week 3 - A Plasticy Stroll in the Countryside&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a lovely sunny day on Sunday so we decided to take the children for a walk. Not long after we had set off I noticed a small piece of plastic in the hedge. The hedges have recently been trimmed and as we walked further we began to notice more and more. I think this plastic is always there but unless you are looking for it you don’t particularly notice it. We decided to collect all the plastic we came across (luckily I had some bio-degradable dog bags in my pocket to collect it in!). By the end of our two mile walk you can see we had picked up quite a lot - some of it crisp and chocolate bar packaging but also lots of bigger pieces which were half buried in the ground.  My new pledge is to pick up at least three pieces of plastic everytime I am out walking in the countryside. A report in Science Magazine estimates that 8.3bn tonnes of plastic has been produced to date. Of this, 6.3bn tonnes of plastic is now waste – a majority of which, some 79%, is in landfill or the natural environment. Of this 6.3bn tonnes only 9% is recycled. If everyone made this pledge think what a difference this could make!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as collecting rubbish I have also been on a quest to find plastic-free cereal. When I can’t buy from local shops I prefer to support the local Co-op rather than some of the bigger supermarket chains due to their ethical credentials. So rather than buying Weetabix (which I knew was wrapped in paper), I bought the Co-op’s own brand instead. I was horrified when my children opened the box to find that the biscuits were wrapped in plastic. I quickly sent the following email to Customer Services, and am yet to hear a reply! Weetabix reverted back to paper after using film in 2012, not because it was better environmentally, but because it is easier to open. I will stick to Weetabix in the future and begin making my own muesli and granola in the future, watch this space for recipes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/weetabix.jpg&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Sir/Madam,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing to enquire why you wrap your wholewheat biscuits in plastic rather than paper like Weetabix do? I believe you to be an ethical company, one of the reasons why I choose to support you rather than other supermarkets, I am surprised that you do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ethical policy on sustainable development states that nature cannot stand a progressive build up of societies waste, particularly materials that cannot degrade into harmless substances and that you recognise that this is a minimum requirement for ecological sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using non-recyclable, single use plastic seems to go completely against this, particularly when there are other viable alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing your reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E.Sheldrake&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 3 - A Plasticy Stroll in the Countryside</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Trouble with Toothpaste</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Trouble with Toothpaste" /><published>2018-01-12T19:39:55+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-12T19:39:55+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-2/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-2---the-trouble-with-toothpaste&quot;&gt;Week 2 - The Trouble with Toothpaste&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have been mainly troubled by toothpaste! So my toothpaste tube has finally got to the point of needing replacing. I didn’t really know where to start looking for a plastic-free toothpaste alternative. I wasn’t overly optimistic after a quick google search came up with nothing. In fact one website stated that no-one manufactured metal toothpaste tubes anymore. I wasn’t keen to start making my own so I went to my local town. I walked past Holland and Barrett and thought that would be a good place to try as they sell a lot of alternative products. They did indeed sell a range of eco and organic toothpaste but all in plastic tubes. After trying a few other places I decided to look in a large local supermarket (naming no names!) and was very surprised to find Euthymol Toothpaste in a metal tube. Although it has a plastic lid I thought this was the best next option before I pluck up the courage to make my own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2836/8947738178_195b5aa707_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Euthymol&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 2 - The Trouble with Toothpaste</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Post-Christmas Blues</title><link href="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post-Christmas Blues" /><published>2018-01-07T19:39:55+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-07T19:39:55+00:00</updated><id>http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/blog/week-1/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-1---post-christmas-blues&quot;&gt;Week 1 - Post-Christmas Blues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first week of myunplasticlife hasn’t been too much of a challenge! Mainly because having just having had Christmas I haven’t felt the need to go shopping. I’m sure hurdles will soon be standing in my way when I begin to run out of supplies. I’m also very lucky to have easy access to the family business - Alder Carr Farm Shop which is also pledging to go plastic free. This means I can easily get many of my staples, in particular fruit and vegetables which in the supermarkets are surrounding in packaging, completely plastic free!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 1 - Post-Christmas Blues</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.myunplasticlife.co.uk/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry></feed>